# REMI DESREUMAUX

fin http://linkedin.com/in/remides Ohttps://github.com/remster85 🗠 remi.desreumaux@gmail.com 🛍 New York City, NY

Looking for a Full Stack Developer role building impactful solutions. 13+ years' experience in designing, developing, maintaining and running technical solutions for investment banking front and middle office.

## **EDUCATION**

Information Systems master's degree - ISEN LILLE, FRANCE, 2003-2008, Valedictorian in Major

# **SKILLS**

- Backend: Java(Expert): Spring Boot, Hibernate C# (Expert) - Python (Intermediate) - TDD, Tests, QA, API
- Frontend: Angular (Advanced), React, Typescript, HTML, CSS, Javascript
- Data: PostgreSQL, SQL Server, DataLake, MongoDB, Sybase, ETL, ELT, SSIS, SSAS
- Messaging: FIX Protocol, MSMQ
- Compute: Docker, Kubernetes, Cloud, Windows VM
- Languages: French (Native), English

# AWARDS and CERTIFICATIONS

- MongoDB for .NET Developers
- Redis for Java Developers
- Azure Devops & Developer Associate
- Public Cloud Security & Digital Champion
- Global Banking Solution IT Expert
- Unix champion
- **Toastmasters International Competent** Communicator and Leader

# WORK EXPERIENCE

**SOCIETE GENERALE AMERICAS**, New York City Prime Brokerage & Equities: 2021-Present Full Stack Developer, Application Lead (since 2024) & Vice President Java, Angular, Docker, Kubernetes, Python

2015-Present

# Front Office P&L analyzer

- Designed and implemented the application: 30+ users, 40+ flows, 7M datapoints calculated daily, 500GB, 2 developers
- Led the 2024 end user satisfaction survey and action plan, achieving a 300% improvement in webpage load times
- Migrated the database from MSSQL to Postgresql, resulting in a 50% cost reduction and a 2X increase in performance
- Migrated computing from obsolete private cloud Gen 1 to Gen 2, mitigating the risk of overpaying infrastructure
- Led multiple technical studies on the product and setup observability

Regulatory impact: \$1 billion P&L capture, calculation and validation for AMER and EMEA on T+1 Business impact: Detection of anomalies in client pricing \$100K Annual NBI, Detection of Uncharged Give Ups worth 53K EUR

# Corporate Action Middle Office booking tool

- Industrialized the application (containerization, CI/CD pipeline, sonar, quality, database) resulting in worldwide expansion
- Adapted the tool to handle T+1 Settlement and met the regulatory requirement on time May 28th, 2024
- Implemented the Capture of Listed and OTC Options leading into the capture of 1 million options/year

### US Treasuries OMS

- Rewrote the Frontend (React to Angular) and Backend (Python to Java) resulting into an alignment of technical stack and preparing for product scope expansion to FX expecting to bring \$100k/month NBI. Fix Protocol through TradeWeb.
- Setup the homologation environment with the vendor TradeWeb to ensure non regression after rewriting

#### Counterparty Credit Risk application interface

• Designed and implemented resulting in the validation of clients' investment strategies from a risk standpoint

#### **Cloud Transformation**

- Studied and Migrated 3 Front Office applications to Public Cloud Azure decreasing company's infrastructure bill by \$25k/year
- Containerized the very first front office application of Investment and Financing Americas and led the migration of around 50

**Commodities**: 2015-2020

Front Office Developer, Vice President (since 2018) & Technical Lead

.NET C#, SSIS, Python, React

#### Index Platform

- Built a data hub for the index commodities business enabler for automation, innovation and operational risk mitigation
- Built a client-facing investment backtesting platform generating business retention and growth
- Developed a Fee based Index Feature (Maintenance, OneShot, Running, In Percent ...) generating 200k/year

#### <u>Devops</u>

Created a digital product to enhance DevOps: 1000+ entries resulting in cost savings equivalent of 2 full-time employees

## Chatbots

- Coded an innovative client-facing Post-trade Fixed Income chatbot leading to Tier 1 client retention
- Innovated and developed a series of chatbots for Front-office, Middle-office and Technology Team to
  offer self-service and monitoring capabilities reducing cost of support, mitigating operational risk, increasing user
  satisfaction

## **SOCIETE GENERALE FRANCE**, Paris La Defense, Front Office Developer

FEB 2013 - OCT 2015

Cross Asset Team

.NET C#, VBA

- Developed micro-services for market and referential data, business processes increasing frequency of change from 3 months to 2 weeks
- Contributed to improve performance of referential data retrieval: 40 million objects moved to a cutting-edge technology data storage
- Introduced usage tracking in the tactical scope of applications that facilitated decommissioning of 10 applications
- Integrated the Team Code to the main line: 8000 lines of code, 20 developers
- Maintained the front office tools (20+ applications developed with an in-house framework)

# **SOCIETE GENERALE AMERICAS,** New York City, Front Office Developer

JUN 2011 - DEC 2012

Commodities Index Trading Desk

.NET C#, VBA

- Built a market Data reconciliation tool: 1 million data points checked/year (still in use as of 2024)
- Built a Deal Reconciliation tool: 50k deals checked/year
- Built an Index Breakdown reporting tool: 5k reports sent to external clients/year (still in use as of 2024)

# HSBC, as FDM Group consultant, Paris, Front Office Developer

OCT 2010 - JUN 2011

Rates Trading Desk

.NET C#, Java, VBA

- Created a Process Monitoring Tool for the team to monitor production in real time
- Ran the quality insurance of Quant libraries
- Migrated 2 applications from VBA to C#

# MAAF, EPO, as Rades consultant, Paris, Java Developer

JAN 2010 - OCT 2010

- Created business monitoring dashboards for European Patent Office
- Created business monitoring dashboards for MAAF

# FRENCH FEDERATION OF TENNIS, as DT consultant, Paris, Java Developer

APR 2009 - OCT 2010

- Built an innovative e-ticketing solution for Roland Garros that received an award
- Maintained a VIP ticketing application for Roland Garros and Paris Masters and secure 2009 season

# **HOBBIES AND OTHER CONTRIBUTIONS**

Running: 8 marathons, 80+ races - Soccer - Traveling: over 50 countries

Contribution to Open Source server Uvicorn: Secure Sockets Layers Context Initialization  $\underline{Link}$ 

Covid Pet Project Remstrava: A platform sitting on top of Strava running from Azure and AWS to experience services